伦敦  苏豪区
星期四
距世界末日还有两天
有什么可以帮忙的吗
Can I help you?
我想买一件你的物质物体
I would like to purchase one of your material objects.
-是书  -书
- Books. - Books.
我们去个私密的地方探讨我的购买吧
Let us discuss my purchase in a private place,
因为我要买
because I am buying,
色情作品吗
Pornography?
色情作品
Pornography.
加百列  后面请
Gabriel, come into my back room.
我们人类很容易感到尴尬
We humans are extremely easily embarrassed.
色情作品必须秘密购买
We must buy our pornography secretively.
人类真是愚蠢
Human beings are so simple...
《比顿太太家务打理大全》
如此容易受愚弄
and so easily fooled.
是啊
Yes.
好样的  你把他们都骗过了
Good job. You-- You fooled them all.
你记得尚达奉吧
You remember Sandalphon?
所多玛和蛾摩拉
Sodom and Gomorrah.
你不是天降正义
You were doing a lot of smiting
就是把人变成盐柱
and turning people into salt.
难以忘记
Hard to forget.
有一股...邪恶的味道
Something smells...evil.
那恐怕是杰弗里·阿彻的书
Oh, that'll be the Jeffrey Archer books, I'm afraid.
我们顺路过来
Well, we just wanted to stop by
问问敌基督的状况
and check on the status of the Antichrist.
怎么  出什么事了
Why? What's wrong?
我是说  如果出了什么事
I-- I mean, if there is something wrong,
我可以叫我的人去处理
I could put my people onto it.
没出事  一切都好
Nothing's wrong. Everything's going perfectly.
发生了很多事  都是好事
There's a lot happening. All good.
都是好事
All good?
一切都在照神圣计划进行
Well, all going according to the Divine Plan.
地狱犬已被放出
The Hell Hound has been set loose,
天启四骑士也在被召唤
and now the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse are being summoned.
死亡  污染  饥荒  战争
Death, Pollution, Famine, War.
是啊
Right.
是谁召唤了他们
Who exactly summons them?
不归我们部门管
Not my department.
这种事我们好像是外包的
I believe we outsource that sort of thing.
要我说  是时候了
About time, that's what I say.
战争不到  何来战争
You can't have a war without War.
尚达奉  说得太妙了
Sandalphon, that is very good.
战争不到  何来战争
You can't have a war without War.
我可能会用到这句话
I might use that.
总之
Anyway...
没问题吗  地狱犬如何了
no problems? How was the Hell Hound?
我没留下观察
I-- I didn't stick around to see.
谢谢你帮我找色情作品
Thank you for my pornography!
干得漂亮
Excellent job.
「战争不到  何来战争」
"You can't have a war without War."
机智
Clever.
欢迎回来  政府外交事务发言人
Welcome back. Now, the government's foreign affairs spokesman
帕姆和萨姆
将对近期愈发加剧的
will be here to comment on the recent increase
国际紧张形势进行点评
in international tensions.
但首先  你知道你冰箱里都有什么吗
But first, do you know what's in your fridge?
早  克劳利
Morning, Crowley.
确认一下情况
Just checking in.
椅子不错
Nice chair.
你们好
Hey, guys.
是敌基督的事
It's about the Antichrist.
嗯  好孩子  像他老子
Yeah. Great kid. Takes after his dad.
我们在国务院的人
Our operatives in the State Department
已安排他一家
have arranged for the child's family
被飞去中东
to be flown to the Middle East.
在那里  他和地狱犬
There, he and the Hell Hound
会被带去米吉多峡谷
will be taken to the Valley of Megiddo.
天启四骑士会开始他们最终的骑乘
The Four Horsemen will begin their final ride.
末日之战将会开启
Armageddon will begin.
最终对决
The final combat.
我们自反叛之日起就在为这一天努力
It's what we've been working towards since we rebelled.
我们是堕落者
We are the fallen.
永远不要忘记
Never forget that.
这种事怎么会忘
Well, it's not the sort of thing you forget.
我不信任你  克劳利
I don't trust you, Crowley.
一切顺利极了
Everything's going just fine.
我又没想堕天
I didn't mean to fall.
我不过是交友不慎
I just hung around the wrong people.
总得有人召唤
Somebody has to summon
天启四骑士
the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse.
但如今  这种事都外包了
But they outsource that sort of thing these days.
这位是召唤者
Meet the Summoner.
他车里有四件货物要送
He has four items to deliver in his van.
他为国际快递公司工作
He works for the International Express Company.
他正在前往昔日的战区送第一份快件
And he's about to make his first delivery in a former war zone.
北非  无主之地
有时候尽管困难重重  和平还是会突然爆发
Sometimes, despite everything, peace breaks out.
人们厌倦了战斗  痛苦和死亡
People get tired of fighting, and pain, and death,
愿意重新开始
and are willing to start all over again.
不好意思  你是谁
Excuse me, who are you?
卡尔麦·金姜  《国家世界周刊》
Carmine Zingiber. National World Weekly.
战地记者
War correspondent.
这是好事  朋友
Well, this is good, my friend.
正好有世界媒体成员来此
It is good that a member of the world press is here
见证我们签署和平协议
to see us sign the peace accord.
那好  麻烦你先签这个  陛下
Right, well, if you'd like to sign this first, Your Highness,
然后是首相和至高领袖
and then the Prime Minister, then the Supreme Leader,
然后我们拍张你们三个的合照
then we'll get a photograph of all three of you together.
等等  他先签
Wait. He signs first?
谁先签只是个形式
It is just a formality who signs first.
形式  你让我在我的国家成为笑柄
A formality? You make me a laughingstock in my country,
还说只是形式
and you call that a formality?
和平协议总得有人先签署
Somebody has to sign the peace agreement first.
没错  就是我
They do, and it's me.
别介意我  女士们先生们
Oh, don't mind me, ladies and gents.
多好的一天
Oh, what a day, eh?
差点儿没找到这地方
Nearly didn't find the place.
有些人就是不肯竖路标
Someone doesn't believe in signposts, eh?
您的包裹  女士
Package for you, miss.
您得签收
You, uh... you have to sign for it.
真是个好地方
Well, it's a lovely place you got here.
一直想来这里度假
Yeah, I always wanted to come here on my holidays.
-终于来了  -把它放下
- Finally. - Put it down.
小甜心
Oh, you sweet thing.
你是不会开枪的  对吧
That's not gonna happen, is it?
抱歉  各位
Sorry, folks.
我很想留下跟你们加深了解
I'd love to stay and get to know you all better...
但我有重任在身
but duty calls.
她是四骑士中的第一个
She's the first of four.
她不到场  战争无从打响
And you can't have a war without her.
她已经消磨时间太久
She's been killing time for so long now.
杀时间  有时也杀人
Time, and sometimes people.
60个世纪的等待终于到了尽头
And now, 60 centuries of waiting are about to end.
战争
好  兆  头
第二集
这也是关于一个女巫
This is also the story of a witch,
一个猎巫人和一本书的故事
a Witchfinder, and a book.
故事从大约360年前
And that story starts about 360 years ago,
英格兰  兰开夏郡
1656年
英格兰最后一场女巫火刑开始
with the last witch burning in England.
猎巫人帕西法少校  都准备好了
Witchfinder Major Pulsifer, all is prepared.
那婆娘在哪
Where is the hag?
在她的小屋里  她毫未起疑
In her cottage. She suspects nothing.
我以为你用大头针试过她了
I thought you'd tested her with a pin.
是的  标准配发的猎巫人大头针
We did. Regulation-issue Witchfinder's pin.
-扎了个遍  -结果呢
- Pricked her all over. - And what was the result?
她说治好了她的关节炎
She said it cured her arthritis.
她还还有什么罪名
Of what else is she accused?
主要是预测未来
Predicting the future, mostly.
她对布科克太太说
She told Mistress Bulcock
「奸淫」将来到镇上
that Adultery would be coming to town.
胡说
Such nonsense.
那是你吧
That's you, isn't it?
不是我
It's not me.
我的名字  猎巫人二等兵麦格斯
My given name, Witchfinder Maggs,
是「不可奸淫」
is Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery.
你可以叫我「猎巫人帕西法少校」
But you can call me "Witchfinder Major Pulsifer".
那他们不叫你「不可奸淫·帕西法」
So they don't call you "Adultery Pulsifer"?
不
They do not.
好奶工
Good milkman...
因为今日我将在烈焰中死去
for today I am to die in flames.
此致  艾格妮丝·风子
Yours, Agnes Nutter.
附注  向你妻子问好
P.S. My best wishes to your wife.
女巫  女巫
Witch! Witch!
他们迟到了
They're late.
我听人说  她跑步
She runs, I have heard tell,
虽然没人追赶她
with no one pursuing her.
她说每天早上
She says running each morning
很不淑女地绕村跑步
in an unladylike manner around the village
有益她的健康
doth improve her health.
太可怕了
Monstrous.
或许那女巫跑时  有隐形的恶魔追她
Perhaps invisible demons pursue the witch as she runs.
不  她说对人有好处
No, she says it's good for you.
她说我们的饮食中该增加纤维
She said we should get more fibre in our diet.
我跟她说  拣出砂砾已经够难了
I told her, I said, it's hard enough picking out the gravel.
她显然是疯了
She is obviously mad.
但我们怎么能确定她是女巫
But how can we be certain she is a witch?
她治好了我的天花
She cured me of the howling pox.
还治好了我儿子的血痢
And cured my son of the bloody flux.
显然是个女巫
Obviously, a witch.
女巫
Witch.
奸淫·帕西法
Adultery Pulsifer...
好人们
good people,
你们真磨蹭
thou art tardy.
我十分钟前就该被点着了
I should have been aflame 10 minutes since.
好了
Right.
风子女士
Mistress Nutter?
这太不寻常了  风子女士
This is most irregular, Mistress Nutter.
聚拢过来  好人们
Gather thee right close, good people.
凑近点  直到火焰几乎灼伤汝等
Come close until the fire near scorch ye,
因为我要汝等见证
for I charge ye that all must see
英格兰最后一位真正的女巫之死
how the last true witch in England dies.
让我的死成为传达给世界的讯息
And let my death be a message to the world.
来吧
Come.
来  聚拢过来
Come. Gather thee close, I say.
让世界记住胡乱插手不解之事者
And mark well the fate of those who meddle
会有何等下场
with such as they do not understand.
该死
Oh, bugger.
此帽子属于猎巫人少校不可奸淫·帕西法
隔壁村的村民们
Among the folk from the next village,
随后开始争论
there was much subsequent debate
这场灾难到底是上帝还是撒旦搞出来的
as to whether this disaster had been sent by God or by Satan.
然而  在艾格妮丝小屋里找到的一张留言
However, a note found in Agnes' cottage
表明了任何神或恶魔的干涉
suggested that any divine or devilish intervention
都在极大程度上受到了艾格妮丝的衬裙的帮助
had been materially helped by Agnes' petticoats,
她在其中藏了50磅的火药
in which she had concealed 50 pounds of gunpowder
火药  瓦楞钉
和30磅的瓦楞钉
and 30 pounds of roofing nails.
该死
Oh, bugger.
艾格妮丝还留下了一只箱子和一本书
Agnes also left behind a box and a book.
是给她女儿和女婿的
They were to be given to her daughter and her son-in-law,
约翰和维德·仪祁
John and Virtue Device.
「亲爱的风子女士
"Dear Mistress Nutter,
我们愉快地附上您著作的样书
we take great pleasure in enclosing your author's copy of your book.
我们相信本书会十分畅销
We trust it will sell in huge numbers,
没错  甚至会印第二版
yea, and be reprinted even unto a second printing.
此致  比尔顿和史盖茨出版社」
Yours, Bilton and Scaggs, publishers."
《艾格妮丝·风子的精妙准确预言书》
The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter.
法国占星家
「如同巅峰时期的诺查丹玛斯再世」
"Reminiscent of Nostradamus at his best."
英国通灵修女
厄苏拉·希普顿
Ursula Shipton.
这是什么意思啊  约翰
What does this mean, John?
意思是  维德  就算艾格妮丝死了
It means, Virtue, that even though Agnes is dead,
我们也必须研究她的书
we must study her book.
因为你母亲能预知未来
For your mother knew the future.
「第2214条预言
"Prophecy 2,214.
1980年12月
In December 1980,
一颗苹果崛起  无人能吃
an Apple will arise no man can eat.
钱财投给乔布斯大师的机器
Invest thy money in Master Jobbes's machine,
财源滚滚  生活无忧」
and good fortune will tend thy days."
这简直是胡说
I mean, this is balderdash.
艾格妮丝留下的那本书
The book Agnes left behind her
是人类历史上仅有的
was the sole prophetic work in all of human history
对接下来的350多年做出了完整的
to consist entirely of completely correct predictions
加利福尼亚州  马里布
且完全正确预言的预言作品
concerning the following 350-odd years.
11年前
是对末日决战之前的一切事件
Being a precise and accurate description
精良而准确的描述
of the events that would culminate in Armageddon.
在每个细节上都完全正确
It was on the money in every single detail.
在敌基督出生的那晚  马里布的一栋房子里
On the night the Antichrist was born, in a house in Malibu,
艾格妮丝·风子的曾曾曾曾曾孙女
Agnes Nutter's great-great-great-great-great granddaughter
正在扉页上涂鸦
was drawing on the title page.
打个比喻  本书刚刚被启动
And, metaphorically, the book had just begun to tick.
《精妙准确预言书》
好了  安娜丝玛  第2214条预言
Okay, Anathema. Prophecy 2,214.
「第2214条预言
"In December 1980,
一颗苹果崛起  无人能吃」
an Apple will arise that no man can eat."
那条太蠢了 妈妈  它没有任何意义
That one's stupid, Mom. It doesn't mean anything.
我妈妈在1980年买了五千股苹果
My mom bought 5,000 shares in Apple in 1980.
如今市值四千万美元
That's worth $40 million today.
好了  第2213条
Okay, 2,213.
「四人骑行  三人并作两人天上飞
"Four shall ride, and three shall ride the sky as two,
一人驾火焰而来
and one shall ride in flames,
不可阻挡
and there shall be no stopping them.
鱼不可  雨不可  恶魔和天使皆不可
Not fish, nor rain, neither devil or angel.
而你也该去现场  安娜丝玛」
And ye shall be there also, Anathema."
你瞧
You see?
她对你是有特别的安排的  亲爱的
She's got special plans for you, mi amor.
艾格妮丝给我们派了个简单任务
Agnes gave us the easy job.
我们只需确保一切都有利于家族
We just had to make sure everything was good for the family.
你将会是拯救世界的人
You're the one that's going to have to save the world.
与此同时  在萨里郡多尔金地区
Meanwhile, in Dorking, Surrey,
不可奸淫·帕西法的
Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery Pulsifer's
曾曾曾曾曾孙
great-great-great-great-great grandson
一小时前就该上床睡觉了
should have been in bed hours ago.
牛顿
Newton?
已经过了你的睡觉时间了  亲爱的
It's after your bedtime, dear.
几分钟就好  妈
Just a few more minutes, Mum.
我在把旧电脑组装回去
I'm putting the old computer back together.
你个小科学家和你那些实验啊
You young scientists and your experiments.
这其实并不算实验  妈
It's not really an experiment, Mum.
我只是换了个插头
I just changed the plug.
现在就可以用了
It'll work now.
我希望电力公司的人
I do hope the man from
这次别太不高兴
the electric isn't going to be upset again.
-这不公平  -别担心  亲爱的
- It's not fair. - Oh, don't worry, love.
这又不是世界末日
It's not as if it's the end of the world.
当下
我想说  祝你新工作好运
I just wanted to say, well, good luck on the new job.
希望这次能顺利
I hope it works out this time.
-不会有问题的  妈  -你只是运气不好
- I'm sure it'll be fine, Mum. - You've just been unlucky.
我给你做了三明治
I made you sandwiches.
你是
And you are?
牛顿·帕西法  薪资出纳
Newton Pulsifer. Wages clerk.
我是新来的
I'm new.
抱歉  我在想
Excuse me, I was just wondering,
有没有什么办法
is there a way that I could
我可以不用电脑做这件事
do this without putting it in the computer?
有没操作薪酬数据库
Is there a way of accessing the wages database...
而不使用电脑的方法
without using a computer?
也许有人可以打印出来给我
Or maybe someone could print it out for me,
然后我可以在纸上完成计算
and then I could do the sums on paper.
有谁期待集训
Okay, who's excited by the training initiative?
举个手
Let's see some hands. Yeah?
我就知会你一声  诺曼
Just so that you know, Norman,
我已经向人力资源递交了投诉
I've registered a complaint with HR
抗议这场狗屁集训
about this whole training initiative nonsense.
这是个团队建设活动  贾尼斯
It's a team-building exercise, Janice.
而且  知会你一声
And, um, just so as you know,
团队里面无个人
there's no "i" In "team", yeah?
而建设需要个人  奈杰尔
But there's two "i's" in "building", Nigel.
活动也需要
And an "i" in "exercise".
嗯  好吧
Yeah. Alright.
麻烦大家认真听我说
So, can I have everybody's attention, please?
抱歉  我敲个「回车」就来
Sorry, I've just got to hit return and I'll be with you.
抱歉  我不太擅长用电脑
Sorry, just not very good with computers.
需要帮忙吗  迪克
Need a hand, Dick?
我的名字其实不叫迪克  那是我的车的名字
My name's not actually Dick. It's the car's name.
你乐意的话  可以问我原因
You can ask me why, if you like.
英国海关
你好
Hello.
安丝娜玛·仪祁
"Athaneema Device"?
安娜丝玛·仪祁  这是个古老的姓
Anathema Device. It's an old family name.
你来到英国的目的是什么
Purpose of your visit to the United Kingdom?
我受一则古老的家族预言指示
Well, I'm commanded by an ancient family prophecy.
将运用我的所有智慧和巫术
I'm going to use all the wisdom and witchcraft at my disposal
直捣黑暗的核心
to hunt down the heart of darkness,
用尽一切方法毁掉它
and then do all that I can to destroy it
以防它毁灭世界
before it brings about the end of the world.
什么
I'm sorry?
度假
Vacation.
你好  妈
Hello, Mum.
新工作吗
The new job?
嗯  非常顺利
Yeah, it's going really well.
他们很棒
They're great.
-他们都爱我  -你们视而不见
- They love me. - Walk past them with your noses in the air.
在家  妈
Bye, Mum.
我们需要惧怕的事只有一件  娘娘腔们
There's only one thing we have to fear, you sissies,
我指的不是全球变暖  也不是核末日
and it's not global warming, and it's not nuclear Armageddon.
虫蛀的庄稼/邪恶的眼神/裸体的舞蹈/崇拜魔鬼
乳头过多/给猫起搞笑的名字
有人能告诉我是什么吗
Can anyone here tell me what it is?
你们不回答
You don't answer.
你们不回答  是因为你们知道是真的
You don't answer, because you know it's true.
他们就藏在我们中间
They are hidden in our midst.
我就是人性和黑暗之间
I'm the thin red line that
那条细细的红线
stands between humanity and the darkness.
-对  我说的是...  -女巫
- Yea, I'm talking about-- - Witches?
对  女巫
Witches.
他们隐藏在正义的面孔背后
They lurk behind a facade of righteousness.
无人可以阻止他们
And there's naebody can stop them...
除了我
but me.
热狗
在过去  猎巫人很受人尊重
In the old days, Witchfinders were respected.
猎巫人将军马修·霍普金斯
Matthew Hopkins, Witchfinder General...
他曾经每抓到一个女巫  就向各个镇子
...he used to charge each town and village ninepence
和村庄收取九便士
for every witch he found.
而他们都乖乖付钱
And they paid.
您是  猎巫人将军吗
Are you, um, Witchfinder General?
我不是
Oh, I am not.
现在已经没有猎巫人将军了
There is no longer a Witchfinder General.
也没有猎巫人上校
Nor is there a Witchfinder Colonel,
猎巫人少校  连猎巫人中尉都没有
a Witchfinder Major, not even a Witchfinder Captain.
但还是有猎巫中士的
There is, however, a Witchfinder Sergeant.
你看看他
And you're looking at him.
很高兴见到你  沙德维尔先生
Well, pleased to meet you, Mr Shadwell.
一杯茶  放九块糖
Cup of tea. Nine sugars.
一袋芝士洋葱片
And a packet of cheese and onion crisps.
这就来
Coming right up.
快掏钱包啊  小伙子
Get your wallet out, laddie.
一点建议  初次会面绝对不要
Bit of advice: you never want to appear tight-fisted
一毛不拔
on first acquaintance.
-谢谢  -而且  不是「沙德维尔先生」
- Thank you. -And it's not "Mr Shadwell".
是「中士」  猎巫人中士沙德维尔
It's "Sergeant". Witchfinder Sergeant Shadwell.
你叫什么名字  小伙子
What's your name, lad?
牛顿  牛顿·帕西法
Newton. Newton Pulsifer.
帕西法
Pulsifer?
你这么一提  这名字好耳熟
That's a familiar name, now you mention it.
你的牙齿是自己的吗
You have your own teeth?
是的
Yes.
-有几个乳头  -什么
- How many nipples have you got? - What?
乳头  小伙子  有几个
Nipples, laddie. How many?
就平常的两个
Just the usual two.
好吧...
Okay...
明天11点到这里
Be here at 11:00 tomorrow.
带上剪刀
Bring scissors.
加入专业队伍
招聘抗击黑暗势力的兼职助理人员
提供制服和基本培训
塔德菲尔德  茉莉小屋
星期四
距世界末日还有两天
放那里就好  非常感谢
Just put it there. Thanks so much.
多美的镇子
What a gorgeous village, huh?
谢谢
Thank you.
塔德菲尔德
好了
Right.
开工
To work.
轻而易举
Easy job.
把敌基督送到  留意他
Deliver the Antichrist. Keep an eye on him.
很好  很简单的工作
Nice, straightforward job, eh?
没有一个恶魔会搞砸的工作  对吧
Not the kind of thing any demon is going to screw up, right?
克劳利的公寓里
The only things in the flat Crowley
得他关心的只有
devotes any personal attention to
盆栽植物
are the houseplants.
他在70年代早期听说了和植物交谈这档事
He had heard about talking to plants in the early '70s,
觉得是个很不错的主意
and thought it an excellent idea.
尽管克劳利所做的
Although "Talking" Is
可能称不上是「交流」
perhaps the wrong word for what Crowley does.
那是斑点吗
Is that a spot?
是吗
Is it?
你们是知道我对叶斑的态度的
Right, you know what I've told you all about leaf spots.
我绝不容忍
I will not stand for them!
你知道自己都做了什么
You know what you've done.
你让我失望了
You've disappointed me.
天啊  天啊
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
都给我听着
Everyone!
跟你们的朋友说再见吧
Say goodbye to your friend.
它就是学不会自我约束
He just couldn't cut it.
这会让你比我更难过
Now, this is going to hurt you so much more than it will hurt me.
你们  给我好好长
And you guys, grow better!
他所做的就是让他们敬畏上帝
What he does is put the fear of God into them.
更准确地说  敬畏克劳利
More precisely, the fear of Crowley.
它们是全伦敦最茂盛
The plants are the most luxurious,
最葱郁  最美丽
verdant and beautiful in London.
也最胆战心惊的盆栽
Also, the most terrified.
《艾格妮丝·风子精妙准确预言书》吗
The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter?
很抱歉  爱莫能助
I'm so sorry, I can't help you.
我当然知道她是谁
Well, of course I know who she was.
生于1600年  因爆炸死于1656年
Born 1600, exploded 1656.
但市面上有她的书
But there are no copies of her book available.
不  我没法开价  我没有
No, I can't name my price. I don't have it.
没人有...
Nobody has--
你真的没必要说那种话
Well, there really is no need for that kind of language.
特蕾西夫人
你好
hello.
我是看了报纸上的广告过来的
I'm here about the advert in the paper.
特蕾西夫人揭开帷幕
Well, Madame Tracy draws aside the veil
除周四外每天下午举办
every afternoon except Thursdays.
我想我看的是另一则广告
I think there must be another advert.
好吧
Oh, right.
进来  亲爱的  你很幸运
Come in, dear. You're lucky.
我的一个常客取消了预约
One of my regulars had to cancel.
除非事先安排  我不接有花样的活儿
Now, I don't do anything kinky except by prior arrangement.
我的膝盖已经不比从前了
And my knees aren't what they were.
还有  如果你想要严格管教
Also, if it's strict discipline you'll be wanting,
你最好现在告诉我  因为穿上皮裙
you'd better tell me now because it can take me half an hour
得花掉我半小时
to squeeze into the leather pinny.
什么
I'm sorry?
你来这里不是寻求亲密的个人放松
Are you not here for intimate personal relaxation
为独具慧眼的绅士释放压力吗
and stress relief for the discerning gentleman?
不
No
我来这是想加入猎巫人部队
I'm here to join the Witchfinder Army.
沙德维尔先生说过有人要来找他
Mr Shadwell said he was expecting a visitor.
他一个人太久了
It's just been him for so long.
你的新兵  沙德维尔先生  看
It's your new recruit, Mr Shadwell, look.
滚远点  婊子
Away with you, harlot.
罪孽深重的女人  荡妇
Scarlet woman. Jezebel.
沙德维尔先生
Oh, Mr Shadwell.
我去给你们泡茶
I'll bring you both tea.
加糖和牛奶吗  亲爱的
Milk and sugar, dear?
他入伍了  荡妇
He's in the army now, Jezebel.
他会自己泡茶的
He'll make his own tea.
污秽魔鬼禁止入内
欢迎来到猎巫人部队  新兵
Welcome to the Witchfinder Army, new recruit.
现在你就是猎巫人二等兵
You are, as of now, Witchfinder Private Pulsifer.
我们曾经权势滔天
We used to be powerful.
我们曾经至关重要
We used to be important.
炼乳  小伙子
Condensed milk, lad.
-我还要...  -九勺糖
- And I take-- - Nine sugars.
对
Exactly.
我们曾是火线
We were the line of fire
阻隔在黑暗和不相信女巫存在的
between the darkness and the poor unsuspecting folk
蒙昧民众之间
who don't believe in witches.
但是  沙德维尔中士
But, Sergeant Shadwell,
这种事现在不是归教会管吗
don't the churches do that these days?
不  小伙子
Nay, laddie.
对抗黑暗势力吗
Against the darkness?
这是战争
It's a war.
知道我们第一武器是什么吗
And you know what our first weapon is?
猎巫人上校达尔林普尔的雷火枪
The Thundergun of Witchfinder
「在他们干掉你之前干掉他们」
Colonel "Get 'em before they get you" Dalrymple?
不  小伙子
Nay, laddie.
它不会再派上用场了
That'll never be used again.
在这个堕落的时代不行
Not in this degenerate age.
很好
Very good.
知道我们用剪刀做什么吗
And you know what we do with them?
不  小伙子
No, lad.
我们阅读
We read.
1.巫师
2.无法解释的现象  现像  现相  事情
你清楚啥意思
然后剪报
And we cut.
嗨  这里是安东尼·克劳利
Hey, this is Anthony Crowley.
你知道该怎么做  要有格调
You know what to do. Do it with style.
我这边没什么线索
No leads yet my end.
你那边有什么线索吗
Anything at your end?
听着  我有了点想法
Listen, I have sort of an idea.
什么
What?
你好  11年前你什么时候交换的孩子
hello. When you did the baby swap 11 years ago,
会不会有什么地方出错了
could something have gone wrong?
什么
What?
-你把那个男孩搞丢了  -是我们搞丢的
- You've lost the boy. - "We've" Lost him.
丢了一个孩子
A child has been lost.
-但你知道他的年龄  -是我们知道
- But you still know his age-- - "We" Know.
他的生日  他11岁
His birthday. He's 11.
-你说得挺简单  -本来就不会太难
- You make it sound easy. - Well, it can't be that hard.
我只是希望他没事
I just hope nothing's happened to him.
什么事  他能有什么事
Happened? Nothing's happened to him.
他就是来搞事的
He happens to everything.
我们只需要找到他的出生记录
So, we only have to find his birth records.
查医院的档案
Go through the hospital files.
-然后呢  -然后我们就会找到那个孩子
- And then what? - And then we find the child.
再然后呢
And then what?
当心行人
Watch out for that pedestrian.
她在街上走  就知道有多大风险
She's on the street. She knows the risk she's taking.
看路  看着路
Just watch the-- Watch the road.
话说回来  医院在哪儿
Wh-Where is this hospital, anyway?
牛津郡附近一个小镇  塔德菲尔德
A village near Oxford, Tadfield.
克劳利  你不能在伦敦中心区开到九十英里
Crowley, you can't do 90 miles per hour in Central London.
-为什么不能  -你会把咱们弄死
- Why not? - You'll get us killed.
会造成不便的灵肉分离
Well, inconveniently discorporated.
音乐  我为什么不放点音乐
Music. Why don't I put on a little... music?
地下丝绒精选集
地下丝绒乐队是什么
What's a Velvet Underground?
你不会喜欢的
You wouldn't like it.
哦  爵士乐
Oh. Bebop.
我还是不敢相信你爸爸让你养它  亚当
I still can't believe your dad let you keep him, Adam.
事实上  我捡到过一只猫
Actually, when I found a cat
不得不发启事说发现走失的猫
we had to put up a notice saying we found a lost cat,
然后我们不得不把它送回去
and then we had to give her back.
这是我的生日  而且它也没带项圈
It's my birthday. And he wasn't wearing a collar.
我们问过了  没人丢了狗
And we asked, and nobody's reported a missing dog.
我家的狗不喜欢我  它假装我不存在
Our dog doesn't like me. It pretends I'm not there.
你们知道吗  我表哥夏洛特说
Did you know that my cousin Charlotte says that in America,
美国的商店里卖39种不同口味的冰淇淋
they have shops that sell 39 different flavours of ice cream.
温斯利戴名叫杰里米
Wensleydale's first name is Jeremy,
但谁都不用这个名字称呼他
but nobody's ever used it,
连他父母也一样  他们叫他「小家伙」
not even his parents, who call him "Youngster".
温斯利戴一家
他跟注册会计师之间的差别
All that stands between Wensleydale
完全是个时间问题
and chartered accountancy is time.
不可能有39种口味的冰淇淋
There aren't 39 different flavours of ice cream.
全世界都没有有39种口味的冰淇淋
There aren't 39 flavours of ice cream in the whole world.
佩帕的名字原本是皮平·凯兰崔尔·月之子
Pepper's given first names were Pippin Galadriel Moonchild.
她在一个命名仪式上被赐予了这个名字
She had been given them in a naming ceremony
那场大会在一个泥泞的小镇里  有几只羊
in a muddy valley field that contained several sheep
数个漏水的聚乙烯帐篷
and a number of leaky polythene tents.
六个月后  厌倦了雨  男人
Six months later, sick of the rain, the men,
先后吃掉大麻作物和帐篷的羊
the sheep who ate first their marijuana crop and then their tents,
佩帕的妈妈回到了塔德菲尔德
Pepper's mother returned to Tadfield
开始学习社会学课程
and enrolled in a Sociology course.
那是有可能的  混合起来就是了
There could be, if you mixed them up.
比如草莓巧克力
You know, strawberry and chocolate.
每个小帮派都需要一个布赖恩
Every gang needs a Brian.
永远邋遢
Always grimy,
永远支持亚当提出来的所有想法和需求
always supportive of anything Adam invents or needs.
香草巧克力
Vanilla and chocolate.
巧克力香草
Chocolate and vanilla.
草莓香草巧克力
Strawberry and vanilla and chocolate.
总之  没人要把狗狗从我身边带走
Anyway, nobody's going to take Dog away from me.
我们永远在一起  是吧  小子
We're together to the end. Aren't we, boy?
蝾螈的眼睛和狗的舌头
Eye of newt and tongue of dog,
西北偏北
north by northwest.
在那
There.
这是西南
And it's southwest.
你一定就在这的某个地方
You must be here somewhere.
有一个女巫住进了茉莉小屋
There's a witch moved in to Jasmine Cottage.
-太蠢了  -才不蠢呢  蠢货
- That's stupid. - It's not stupid, stupid.
亨德森太太跟我妈妈说
Mrs Henderson told my mother
那人订了一份女巫的报纸
that the lady there gets a witches' newspaper.
不好意思  我爸说世上没有什么女巫
Excuse me. My father says there's no such thing as witches.
女巫有自己的报纸听上去挺合理的
It makes sense that witches would have their own newspaper.
我爸爸就订了《垂钓者邮报》
My dad gets the Angler's Times,
我打赌世上的女巫肯定比垂钓者多
and I bet there's loads more witches than anglers.
闭嘴  我没说完呢
Shut up. I'm trying to tell you things.
那报纸叫《通灵新闻报》
It's called the Psychic News.
她是个女巫
She's a witch.
事实上  再也没有女巫了
Actually, there are no more witches,
因为我们发明了科学
because we invented science
所有牧师都会烧死女巫  这是为她们好
and all the vicars set fire to the witches for their own good.
这叫西班牙宗教审判
It was called the Spanish Inquisition.
我觉得到处放火烧死别人  肯定是不允许的
I don't reckon it's allowed, going round setting fire to people.
要不人们岂不是玩起来没个够
Otherwise people'd be doing it all the time.
如果你是牧师就没问题
It's alright if you're a vicar
这样做还能防止女巫下地狱
and it stops the witches from going to hell.
我想  只要能摆正心态  她们一定感激不尽
So I expect they'd be quite grateful if they understood it properly.
我们能组织一场新的西班牙宗教审判
We could be the new Spanish Inquisition.
事实上  我们不能当西班牙宗教审判官
Actually, we can't be the Spanish Inquisition,
因为我们不是西班牙人
because we're not actually Spanish.
我去过巴塞罗那  我可以教你们西班牙语
I've been to Barcelona. I can teach you Spanish.
他们经常说「精彩」
They say "olé" a lot.
我们在烧女巫之前  应该先联系一下
We should practice before we start burning witches.
从小处做起  稳扎稳打
We should start small and work our way up.
交给我吧
Leave it to me.
这里是塔德菲尔德地区  有没有一种似曾相识的感觉
This is the Tadfield area. Does it look familiar yet?
的确很熟悉
You know, it does.
我记得这附近有个空军基地
I think there's an air base around here somewhere.
基地
Air base?
你不会以为美国外交官的妻子
Well, you don't think American diplomats' wives
通常都在不知什么地方的
usually give birth in little religious hospitals
修会小医院里生孩子吧
in the middle of nowhere, do you?
必须让一切显得自然而然
No, it all had to seem to happen naturally,
下塔德菲尔德有一处空军基地
so there's an air base at Lower Tadfield.
孩子要生了  基地医院还没做好准备
Things started to happen, base hospital isn't ready.
我们的内应就顺水推舟地说
"Oh", our man there said.
「沿这条路走有家产科医院」
"There's a birthing hospital just down the road."
一切搞定
And there we were.
是个相当不错的计划
Rather good organisation.
完美无瑕
Flawless.
这本该奏效的
It should have worked.
邪恶总是暗藏自我毁灭的种子
But evil always contains the seeds of its own destruction.
不管一个邪恶计划多么缜密
No matter how well-planned,
多么周详
how foolproof an evil plan,
无论表面上进行得多么成功
no matter how apparently successful it may seem upon the way,
它终将从罪孽的悬崖上跌落并消亡
in the end it will founder on the rocks of iniquity and vanish.
但在我看来  这不过是一次失误
For my money it was just an ordinary cock-up.
-嘿  小家伙们  -你好
- Hey, guys. - Hi.
帽子很帅
Nice hat.
这其实是用纸板做的
Actually, we made it out of cardboard.
这是为了我们的游戏
It's for our game.
很时髦  你们在玩什么
Stylish. What are you guys playing?
英式宗教审问
The British Inquisition.
快走  温斯利戴
Come on, Wensleydale.
听起来很有趣  这游戏怎么玩
Sounds like fun. How does the game work?
我是大审判官  布莱恩是首席行刑人
I am chief inquisitor. Brian is head torturer.
我们正在寻找女巫
And we're trying to find a witch.
听起来很合理啊
Sounds very sensible.
-怎么找女巫  -看好了
- How do you do that? - Watch.
汝可是女巫
Art thou a witch?
精彩【】
Olé?
是
Yes?
你不能说是  你要说不
You can't say yes. You've got to say no.
然后呢
Then what?
然后我们就对你用刑  让你承认
Then we torture you until you say yes.
慢着  你们要对他用刑
Wait, you're going to torture him?
我们造了一台拷问机
We built a torturing machine.
这看起来像个秋千
It looks like a swing.
但是  在这种情况下
But, obviously, in this situation,
我其实是个女巫
I actually am a witch.
我有一顶尖尖的大帽子
I have a big pointy hat,
我们家里还有只猫  而且
and we have a cat at home, and--
我还借来了妈妈的扫帚
and I borrowed Mum's broom.
谁也没说你不能当女巫
Look, no one's saying you can't be a witch,
但你要说你不是女巫
but you just have to say you're not a witch.
如果我们一问  你就马上承认
There's no point taking all this trouble
我们干吗要费这么大劲
if you're going to go round saying yes the minute we ask you.
-你要说不是  -但是...
- Just say no. - But--
汝可是女巫  邪恶的老丑婆
Art thou a witch, oh, evil crone?
不好意思  亚当  为什么是我在做苦力
Excuse me, Adam, why must I do all the work?
我在受刑  真的很痛苦
I'm being tortured here. Actually, this is very painful.
我在考虑承认自己是女巫
I am thinking of admitting to being a witch.
如果不让我玩  我就回家了
I'm going to go home if I can't have a go.
我不明白为什么乐子全让邪恶女巫得去了
Don't see why evil witches should have all the fun.
你得继续推我呀
You have to keep pushing.
-嘿  孩子  -什么
- Hey, kid. - Yeah?
-我能问你点事吗  -行啊
- Can I ask you something? - Yeah.
有没有见过巨大的野兽或发生过奇怪的事
Are there any great beasts or strange things happening?
这有条狗  它就是只野兽
Well, there's Dog. I mean, he's a beast.
过来  狗狗  打个招呼
Come on, Dog, say hello.
我要找的不是它
Not what I was looking for.
等一下  我得给他们下指令
Hold on. I have to tell them what to do.
好吧  邪恶女巫温斯利戴  别再玩了
All right, evil witch Wensleydale, don't do it again.
现在你从折磨人的秋千上下来
And now you get off the torturing swing
换别人玩一会儿
and let someone else have a turn.
好吧  你们这些孩子都很有趣
Right, well, you kids are hilarious,
但我要继续找了  再会
but I'm going to keep looking, so, bye.
塔德菲尔德庄园
你确定我们来对地方了
Are you sure this is the right place?
这里看起来不像是医院
This-- This doesn't look like a hospital.
而且
And...
我感觉到了爱
...it feels loved.
不会  绝对是这个地方
No, it's definitely the place.
什么叫「感觉到了爱」
What do you mean "loved"?
意思就跟你说「我不喜欢这地方
Well, I mean the opposite of when you say,
令人毛骨悚然」截然相反
"I don't like this place. It feels spooky".
我不会说这种话  我爱毛骨悚然
I don't ever say that. I like spooky.
我是毛骨悚然的死忠粉  我们去找修女谈谈
Big spooky fan, me. Let's go talk to some nuns.
蓝的
Blue?
这是颜料
It's paint.
你们两个都被射中了
You've both been hit!
你们到底会不会玩
I don't know what you think you're playing at right--
-真好玩  -鬼才觉得好玩
- Well, that was fun. - Well, yes, fun for you.
看看我的外套
Look at the state of this coat.
180多年来我精心养护
I've kept this in tip-top condition for over 180 years now.
这块污渍永远洗不掉了
I'll never get this stain out.
用神迹把它搞掉
You could miracle it away.
对  但是
Yes, but...
但我始终会记得那里有块污渍
well, I would always know the stain was there.
我是说  在内心深处
Underneath, I mean.
谢谢
Thank you.
这枪令人印象深刻
Impressive hardware.
我仔细看了下这把枪
I've looked at this gun.
根本就不是一把正经枪
It's not a proper one at all.
它只能发射彩弹
It just shoots paintballs.
你们不是都反对枪支的吗
Don't your lot disapprove of guns?
只要掌握在正确的人手中
Unless they're in the right hands.
有助于论证他们的道德论观点
Then they give weight to a moral argument.
我想是这样的
I think.
道德论观点  认真的吗
A moral argument? Really?
走吧
Come on.
绝对是这儿没错
This is definitely the place.
管理培训不再是
Management training no longer meant
观看一大堆毫无现实意义的幻灯片
watching half a dozen unreliable PowerPoint presentations.
塔德菲尔德庄园
会议和管理培训中心  融合与发展之地
联合世界控股公司  主动出击课程
现今的公司不再止步于此
Firms these days expected more than that.
他们想要储备领导力的高潜人才
They wanted to establish leadership potential,
团队合作与主观能动性
group cooperation and initiative,
所以他们的员工可以自由地
which allowed their employees to fire paintballs
向激怒他们的同事发射彩弹
at any colleagues who irritated them.
不知道修女们去哪儿了
Wonder where the nuns went.
克劳利正在翻阅的Tadfield庄园的宣传册
The brochure for Tadfield Manor Crowley is inspecting
没有提到任何类似这样的内容
fails to contain any sentences along the lines of,
11年前  这座大宅还是撒旦教会的女修道院
"Until 11 years ago, the manor was used as a hospital
虽说她们对执行邪恶计划并不特别在行」
by an order of Satanic nuns who weren't actually very good at it".
会计部的米莉给我胳膊肘上来了一下
Millie from Accounts caught me on the elbow.
-谁赢了  -你们都会输
- Who's winning? - You're all going to lose.
你  你刚刚到底干了什么
What... What the hell did you just do?
他们想要真枪
Well, they wanted real guns,
我给了他们想要的
so I gave them what they wanted.
我一直跟你们说不要相信采购部的人
I always said you couldn't trust those people from Purchasing.
一群混蛋
The bastards.
外面的人在互相射击
There are people out there shooting at each other.
这有助于论证他们的道德争论
Well, it lends weight to their moral argument.
每个人都有自由意志
Everyone has free will,
其中包括杀人的权利
including the right to murder.
你可以把它当成是宇宙的缩影
Just think of it as a microcosm of the universe.
我想成为一名图形设计师
I wanted to be a graphics designer,
为滚石乐队设计唱片封面
design LPs for the Rolling Stones,
但我的就业指导老师说他没听说过这个乐队
but the careers teacher said he hadn't heard of them.
于是整整36年  我都在核对BF-18表
So I spent 36 years double-checking form BF-18.
他们就不能对我说
They couldn't just say,
「诺曼  你提前退休了
"Oh, Norman, we're giving you early retirement."
送你一块纪念手表  滚回家养你的金盏花」
Have a watch, bugger off and tend your marigolds".
如果他们想要开战
Well, if they want war...
我们就奉陪到底
we're going to give them war.
好了  伙计们  我们去干死那群狗杂种
Okay, guys, let's get the bastards.
他们在互相残杀
They're murdering each other.
不  不会有人被杀的
No, they aren't. No one's killing anyone.
他们都会奇迹般地侥幸存活
They're all having miraculous escapes.
否则就没意思了
It wouldn't be any fun otherwise.
你知道吗  克劳利
You know, Crowley,
我总是说  在内心深处
I've always said that deep down,
你是个特别善...
you really are quite a nice...
闭嘴
Shut it!
我是个恶魔  我不善良
I'm a demon. I'm not nice.
我从来都不善良  善良是一个庸俗的词儿
I'm never nice. Nice is a four-letter word.
-我不许...  -不好意思  先生们
- I will not have... - Excuse me, gentlemen.
很抱歉打扰了  能为你们效劳吗
Sorry to break up an intimate moment. Can I help you?
-你  -圣徒啊恶魔啊  克劳利大人
- You. - Saints and demons preserve us, it's Master Crowley.
没必要这么做
You didn't have to do that.
你可以直接问她的
You could have just asked her.
当然  当然  不  是的
of course, of course. No. Yeah.
「不好意思  女士  我们是两个超自然生灵
"Excuse me, ma'am, we're two supernatural entities"
在寻找声名狼藉的撒旦之子的下落
just looking for the notorious Son of Satan.
能否请您帮我们寻找呢」
"Wonder if you might help us with our enquiries?"
你好
Look... hello.
你不会恰好是
You weren't by any chance,
11年前在这个修道院的修女吧
a nun here at this convent 11 years ago, were you?
我是
I was.
魔鬼的幸运
Luck of the devil.
我交给你的那婴儿去哪儿了
What happened to the baby I gave you?
我把他和美国大使的儿子掉了包
I swapped him with the son of the American ambassador.
他真是个好人
Such a nice man.
曾经是斯文顿的大使
He used to be ambassador to Swindon.
后来特蕾莎修女过来把另一个孩子带走了
Then Sister Theresa Garrulous came and took the other baby away.
这位美国大使  他叫什么名字
This American ambassador, what was his name?
他是从哪里来的  他把孩子带去哪了
Where did he come from and what did he do with the baby?
我不清楚
I don't know.
档案  一定有档案留下
Records. There must have been records.
没错  有很多档案
Yes. There were lots of records.
保存档案是我们的专长
We were very good at keeping records.
那它们在哪儿呢
Well, where are they?
火灾中烧毁了
Burned in the fire.
哈斯塔
Hastur!
你对这个孩子还有任何印象吗
Well, is there anything you remember about the baby?
他的小脚趾头很可爱
He had lovely little toesie-woesies.
走了
Let's go.
你会醒来
You will wake,
你会梦到自己最喜欢的事情
having had a lovely dream about whatever you like best.
照理说他会出现的  不是吗
You'd think he'd show up, wouldn't you?
你觉得咱们能通过某种方式找到他吗
You'd think we could detect him in some way.
他不会出现  不会出现在我们眼前
He won't show up. Not to us.
保护性伪装
Protective camouflage.
连他自己都察觉不到
He won't even know it,
但本能会让他避开诡秘超自然力的窥探
but his powers will keep him hidden from prying occult forces.
诡秘超自然力
Occult forces?
你和我
You and me.
我不诡秘
I'm not occult.
天使不会诡秘  我们神圣优雅
Angels aren't occult. We're ethereal.
有别的办法可以找到他吗
Is there some other way of locating him?
老天  我怎么知道
How the heaven should I know?
末日之战只发生一次
Armageddon only happens once, you know.
没机会一次次尝试  直到搞对为止
You don't get to go round again until you get it right.
但我知道一件事  如果我们找不到他
But I know one thing, if we don't find him,
那就不是一切战争的终结
it won't be the war to end all wars.
而是一切的一切的终结
It'll be the war to end everything.
大多数有关巫术的书籍
Most books on witchcraft
都会告诉你女巫们工作时赤身裸
will tell you that witches work naked.
这是因为大多数有关巫术的书籍都是男人写的
This is because most books on witchcraft are written by men.
「幽暗的夜晚  闪烁的月亮」
"Darksome night and shining moon..."
加油啊
Come on.
对这整片区域  我感觉非常奇怪
There's a very peculiar feeling to this whole area.
我很惊诧你居然感觉不到
I'm astonished you can't feel it.
我没有任何不寻常的感觉
I don't feel anything out of the ordinary.
但这里到处都给我这个感觉
But it's everywhere. All over here.
爱
Love.
强烈的转瞬即逝的爱意
Flashes of love.
你简直可笑
You're being ridiculous.
我们现在最不需要的就是...
Last thing we need right now is...
你撞到人了
You hit someone.
我没有
I didn't.
是有人撞了我
Someone hit me.
要有光
Let there be light.
你是怎么弄的
How the hell did you do that?
我想我是撞到头了
I think I hit my head.
没事  没骨折
That's it. No bones broken.
我的自行车
My bike.
这些老物件  复原能力超强
Amazingly resilient, these old machines.
你要去哪里
Where do you need to get to?
不  我们不能送她
No, no, we're not giving her a lift.
绝不可能  没地方放自行车
Out of the question. There's nowhere to put the bike.
除了自行车架
Except for the bike rack.
上车吧  亲爱的
Do get in, my dear.
我们送你去哪
So, where are we taking you?
回村里  我会给你们指路
Back to the village. I'll give you directions.
BGM: Bicycle Race by Queen
♪自行车♪
♪ Bicycle ♪
♪自行车  自行车♪
♪ Bicycle, bicycle ♪
♪我想骑我的♪
♪ I want to ride my ♪
♪自行车♪
♪ Bicycle ♪
♪自行车  自行车♪
♪ Bicycle, bicycle ♪
我的车没有变速器
Listen, my bike, it didn't have gears.
我知道我的自行车没有变速器
I know my bike didn't have gears.
左转
Make a left.
主啊  请治好那辆车吧
Lord, heal this bike.
我有点昏头了
I got carried away.
你们可以让我在这儿下车
You can drop me off here.
《艾格妮丝·风子的精妙准确预言书》
看  没有变速器
Look, no gears.
-就是一辆非常普通的脚踏车  -自行车
- Just a perfectly normal velocipede. - Bicycle.
咱们可以走了吗
Can we get on?
上车  天使
Get in, angel.
♪我想骑我的♪
♪ I want to ride my ♪
♪自行车♪
♪ Bicycle ♪
♪自行车  自行车♪
♪ Bicycle, bicycle ♪
喂  亲爱的  事情如何了
Hola, mi amor. How is it going?
很糟
Lousy.
你有任何进展吗  找那个...
Any progress in finding the...?
找年轻的野兽和小只的野兽吗
The Young Beast and the Lesser Beast?
肯定在村子最北边
It must be at the north end of the village.
我确定
I'm certain of it.
但我就是找不到在哪
I just can't figure out where.
你用你的钟摆了吗
Have you used your pendulum?
妈  我又不是小孩子
Mom, I'm not a kid.
如果我离得太近  信号会吞噬我
If I get too close, the signal swamps me.
远一些  我又找不到准确的位置
Further away, I can't get an accurate fix.
亲爱的  答案永远在书中
Mi amor, the answers are always in the book.
只是有时你在事情发生后  才明白其中含义
It's just sometimes you don't see them till afterwards.
那本书
The book.
天  妈  我待会儿给你打回去
Holy shit, Mom. I'm going to have to call you back.
我们可以找个人类去寻找他
You know, we might get another human to find him.
-什么  -人类擅长寻找其他人类
- What? - Humans are good at finding other humans.
他们干这行已经有数千年了
They've been doing it for thousands of years.
而这个孩子有一部分是人类
And the child is partly human.
其他人类也许可以感觉到他
Other humans might be able to sense him.
他是敌基督
He's the Antichrist.
他有感觉到他
He's got an automatic defence thingy.
怀疑会从他身边滑过  就像
Suspicion slides off him like...
水会从什么东西身边滑过
whatever it is water slides off.
有更好的主意吗
Got any better ideas?
有半个更好的点子也行
Or one single, better idea?
我还是不懂你为什么让他养那只狗
I still don't know why you let him keep that dog.
那天是他生日  我也不知道
It was his birthday. And, I don't know,
他看着那只狗的样子
the way that he was looking at the dog
还有狗回看他的样子
and the dog was looking at him.
让你觉得他们是天生的伴儿
As if they were made for each other.
亚瑟  有时候你真的心太软
Arthur, you are a softy sometimes.
我讨厌这样说我
I resent that remark.
-狗在哪儿  -栓在外边
- Where's the dog now? - Tied up outside.
亚当问可不可以把狗带到他房间
Adam asked if he could have him in his room,
但我说绝对不行
but I said absolutely not.
我说「绝对不行」
"Absolutely not", I said.
来吧  狗狗
Come on, Dog.
你干什么去了
What was that about?
只是看看亚当
Just checking on Adam.
他那么甜
He's quite sweet, you know...
睡着的时候
when he's asleep.
是啊  睡着的时候
When he's asleep, yeah.
听着  有件事我需要告诉你
Look, there's something I should tell you.
我有一套情报网
I have a... "Network"
训练有素的人类特工
of highly trained human agents
散布在全国各地
spread across the country.
现在  我可以让他们去找那男孩
Now, I could set them searching for the boy.
是吗  我也有类似的组织
You do? I actually... I actually have something similar.
人类特工
Human operatives.
天  你认为应该让他们联手吗
Gosh, do you think they ought to work together?
我看不是个好主意
I don't think that's a very good idea.
从政治上说  我的人还不够
My lot are not very sophisticated,
成熟老练
politically speaking.
是  我的也如此
No, no, neither are mine.
那我们就各自联络人手去找男孩
So we tell our respective operatives to look for the boy?
除非你有更好的主意
Unless you have a better idea?
-鸭子  -什么鸭子
- Ducks! - What about ducks?
水会从鸭子身边滑过
They're what water slides off.
请你好好开车
Just drive the car, please.
如果你让全世界的人站成一列
You know, if you lined up everyone in the whole world
让他们形容地下丝绒乐队的音乐
and asked them to describe the Velvet Underground,
没有一个会用「爵士乐」这个词
nobody at all would say "Bebop".
后面有本书
There's a book back there.
不是我的  我不读书
Well, it's not mine. I don't read books.
肯定是你开车撞到的那个年轻女士我的麻烦已经够多了的
It has to belong to the young lady you hit with your car.
我的麻烦已经够多了
I'm in enough trouble as it is.
不打算去归还失物
I'm not going to start returning lost property.
那是你们天使该做的
That's what your lot do.
《艾格妮丝·风子的精妙准确预言书》
你何不把书寄到塔德菲尔德邮局
Why don't you just send it to the Tadfield post office,
收信人就写骑自行车的美国疯婆娘
addressed to "the mad American woman with the bicycle"?
好极了  好的
Jolly good, yes. Rather.
那我们去联络各自的人类特工
Right, so we'll both contact our respective human operatives, then?
好的
All right.
-你还好吗  -非常好
- Are you alright? - Perfectly, yes.
不能再好了
Tip-top.
-没治了  -没治了
- Absolutely tickety-boo. - Tickety-boo?
路上小心
Mind how you go.
好吧
Right.
事情是这样的
Well, that was a thing.
《艾格妮丝·风子的精妙准确预言书》
亚茨拉斐尔特别为自己的预言书藏品感到自豪
Aziraphale was particularly proud of his books of prophecy.
几乎都是第—版
First editions, usually.
而且每本都有签名
And every one was signed.
他有吉普赛人马撒和伊格内修斯西比拉
He had Martha the Gypsy and Ignatius Sybilla
还有奥托维尔·宾斯
and Ottwell Binns.
诺查丹玛斯为他写下
Nostradamus had signed,
「致我的老朋友亚茨拉菲尔  最美好的祝福」
"To myne olde friend Azerafel, with beste wishes".
谢顿大妈在他的书上洒了饮料
Mother Shipton had spilled drink on his copy of her book.
他甚至有一卷
He even owned an original scroll
帕特莫斯岛圣约翰手书的原稿
in the handwriting of St John the Divine of Patmos,
此人的《启示录》是空前绝后的畅销书
whose "Revelation" had been the all-time best seller.
但有一本书他一直不曾拥有
But there was one book he didn't have.
一本他仅仅有所耳闻的书
One book he had only heard of.
《艾格妮丝·风子的精妙准确预言书》
The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter.
「3008
"3,008:
当天使读到我的文字
When that the angel readeth these words of mine,
在他那满是别人书籍的书店
in his shop of other men's books,
末日便已真正临近
then the final days are certes upon us.
大张双眼
Open thine eyes to understand.
大张双眼细细看
Open thine eyes and read, I do say,
傻瓜权天使
foolish principalitee,
汝之可可冷掉了」
for thy cocoa doth grow... cold".
「汝之可可冷掉了」
"Thy cocoa doth grow cold"?
什么可可
What cocoa--
3080  关于自己身份  他所言不实
有消息吗  找到失踪的敌基督了吗
Any news? Found the missing Antichrist yet?
没有  没消息  什么都没有
No. No news. Nothing. Nothing at all.
如果我知道什么  我肯定告诉你了
If I had anything, I would tell you, obviously.
马上告诉你  我们是朋友  你为什么要问
Immediately. We're friends. Why would you even ask?
我这边也没消息
There's no news here either.
找到什么就给我打电话
Call me if you find anything.
当然  为什么你会觉得我不会打
Absolutely. Why would you think I wouldn't?
3817  野兽的数字在圣约翰的《启示录》记录
于塔德菲尔德将彼呼唤
汝呼唤之时  小野兽人立如舞蹈
数字
将彼呼唤
于塔德菲尔德
等等
Hang on.
凡有明悟的
就让他计算那兽的数字
因为是人的数字  它的数字是六百六十六
"Let him that hath understanding count the number of the beast,
因为是人的数字
for it is the number of a man.
它的数字是六百六十六
And his number is six hundred threescore and six."
不可能这么简单吧
It can't be that simple, can it?
当然  前面要加上塔德菲尔德的区号
I'd have to put the Tadfield area code first, of course.
六
塔德菲尔德046666  我是亚瑟·扬
Tadfield, 0-4-6-triple-6. Arthur Young here.
爸爸  看  我让狗狗用后腿站起来了
Dad, look, I got Dog to walk on his hind legs!
人立
对不起  打对电话了
Sorry, right number!